# **Deniz Engin**

+33769012293

☑ deniz.engin@inria.fr

**Website** 

Google Scholar

in Linkedin

GitHub



#### **Research Interests**

I am interested in Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing, focusing on understanding videos and addressing related questions under various forms of supervision. I aim to create innovative solutions to enrich our vision and language understanding. I have experience in diverse vision and language projects, including facial expression recognition, image dehazing, detecting and verifying signatures, and multimodal document classification for academic and industry-based projects, and published research papers.

#### **Education**

2020 – 2024 University of Rennes - Rennes, France

PhD, Computer Science

Subject: Multimodal Video Understanding Supervisor: Yannis Avrithis, Teddy Furon

2014 – 2017 | Istanbul Technical University - Istanbul, Turkey

M.Sc., Electronics Engineering
Erasmus Program - KU Leuven, Belgium
Thesis title: "Facial Expression Pair Matching"

## **Professional Experiences**

Jul. 2016 - Jan. 2018

Sep. 2020 – Feb. 2024 PhD Student Inria – Rennes, France

Proposed parameter-efficient zero-shot and few-shot VideoQA: Publication [1] Proposed a knowledge-based VideoQA method collaboration with InterDigital: Publication [2]

Sep. 2020 – Jun. 2022 Researcher InterDigital – Rennes, France

Worked on multimodal video understanding projects, specifically focusing on Video Captioning and VideoQA: Publication [2]

Jan. 2018 – Mar. 2020 📕 R & D Engineer Specialist Yapı Kredi Technology – Istanbul, Turkey

Developed offline signature detection & verification system: Publication [3] Developed multimodal document classification system: Publication [4]

Jul. 2017 – Sep. 2017 Research Intern EPFL Signal Processing Lab (LTS5) – Lausanne, Switzerland

Cross-Pose Facial Expression Recognition via Transfer Learning: Publication [5]

Researcher ITU SiMiT Lab – Istanbul, Turkey
Single Image Dehazing via CycleGAN: Publication [6]

Facial Expression Recognition via Transfer Learning: Publication [7]

### **Selected Publications**

- **D. Engin** and Y. Avrithis, "Zero-shot and few-shot video question answering with multi-modal prompts," in *Proc. ICCV Workshops*, 2023. [Oral Presentation].
- **D. Engin**, F. Schnitzler, N. Q. Duong, and Y. Avrithis, "On the hidden treasure of dialog in video question answering," in *Proc. ICCV*, 2021.
- **D.** Engin\*, A. Kantarci\*, S. Arslan, and H. K. Ekenel, "Offline signature verification on real-world documents," in *Proc. CVPR Workshops*, 2020.
- **D. Engin**, E. Emekligil, B. Oral, S. Arslan, and M. Akpinar, "Multimodal deep neural networks for banking document classification," in *Proc. IMMM*, 2019. [Best Paper Award].
- **D. Engin**, C. Ecabert, H. K. Ekenel, and J.-P. Thiran, "Face frontalization for cross-pose facial expression recognition," in *Proc. EUSIPCO*, 2018.
- **D.** Engin\*, A. Genç\*, and H. Kemal Ekenel, "Cycle-Dehaze: Enhanced cyclegan for single image dehazing," in *Proc. CVPR Workshops*, 2018.
- **D. Engin** and H. K. Ekenel, "Facial expression pair matching," in *Proc. SIU*, 2017.

#### **Skills**

- Python, C, MATLAB, Unix Shell Scripting, SQL, Git, Docker
- Pytorch, TensorFlow, Keras

### Languages

- Turkish Native Proficiency
- English Full Professional Proficiency
- French Elementary Proficiency

## **Summer Schools & Symposiums**

ICVSS 2022 International Computer Vision Summer School, Sicily, Italy. (10 - 16 Jul.)

ELLIS 2021 ELLIS Doctoral Symposium, Tübingen, Germany. (27 Sep. - 1 Oct.)

PAISS 2021 PRAIRIE/MIAI Artificial Intelligence Summer School, Online. (5 – 9 Jul.)

### **Awards and Achievements**

2019 Best Paper Award at IMMM 2019

2018 ECCV Woman in Computer Vision Workshop Travel Grant

2016-2017 Research Scholarship from National Research & Technical Council of Turkey

2015-2016 Exchange Student Grant by Erasmus Program

#### **Reviewer Activities**

2023 CVPR, ICCV

2022 ECCV